Witness the birth of an American tradition.
The First Purge is a action, horror, thriller film directed by Gerard McMurray.
To push the crime rate below one percent for the rest of the year, the New Founding Fathers of America
test a sociological theory that vents aggression for one night in one isolated community.
But when the violence of oppressors meets the rage of the others, the contagion will
explode from the trial-city borders and spread across the nation.
Dmitri Cimber, played by Y'lan Noel.
Nya Charms, played by Lex Scott Davis.
Isaiah Charms, played by Joivan Wade.
Freddy, played by Steve Harris.
Dolores, played by Mugga.
Arlo Sabian / Chief of Staff, played by Patch Darragh.
The First Purge is a 2018 American dystopian action horror film serving as a
prequel to the The Purge film series and the fourth installment overall.
Written by James DeMonaco and directed by Gerard McMurray, it is the
first film in the franchise not directed by DeMonaco.
It stars Y'lan Noel, Lex Scott Davis, Joivan Wade, and Steve Harris.
The film depicts the origins of the annual "Purge": a 12-hour period in which all crime in
America is decriminalized as a means to reduce crime for the rest of the year.
The event originates as an experiment conceived by a political party called the New Founding Fathers of America and confined to Staten Island with the promise that those
who stay on the island for its duration will be paid a large sum of money, but the NFFA are determined to get the results they want by any means necessary.
The First Purge was released on June 19, 2018, by Universal Pictures.
It grossed over $137 million worldwide, becoming the highest-grossing entry in the
franchise, but received mixed reviews from critics like its predecessors.
The fifth installment, The Forever Purge, was released on July 2, 2021.
The film explores themes of new york city, new
jersey, dystopia, sequel, prequel.
The tone is dark and intense.